Guide to the Paul Oskar Kristeller Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Iter Italicum, 1949-1997
  - Subseries VI.3: Manuscript, 1987-1997
    This subseries includes drafts and proofs (many corrected in Kristeller's hand) of the Iter Italicum manuscript. This subseries includes drafts of the work's index, as well as notes for future addenda to the work and possible inclusions for later editions.
    - Preface (Box 146)
    - Preface: Volume V, 1987-1989 (Box 146)
    - Manuscript Drafts, (4 Folders) (Box 146)
    - Australia- Austria (Box 146)
    - Austria (Box 146)
    - Belgium, (2 Folders) (Box 146)
    - Denmark (Box 146)
    - Eire (Ireland)- France (Box 146)
    - France, (3 Folders) (Box 146)
    - Germany, Democratic Republic of (East Germany), (2 Folders) (Box 146)
    - Germany, Federal Republic of (West Germany), (7 Folders) (Box 147)
    - Great Britain, (7 Folders) (Box 147)
    - Greece-Mexico (Box 147)
    - Netherlands (Box 147)
    - New Zealand-Poland (Box 147)
    - Portugal-South Africa (Box 148)
    - Spain, (6 Folders) (Box 148)
    - Index: Volume VI, 1994-1995, (8 Folders) (Box 148)
      (includes the manuscript and corrected proofs)
    - Addenda, 1994-1997, (2 Folders) (Box 148)
- Series VII: Notebooks and Notes, 1920-1990
  This series contains research notes, correspondence with libraries and colleagues, and some manuscript drafts related to various areas of Kristeller's research interests.
  - Subseries VII.1: Notebooks on the History of Universities, 1940s-1987
    These notebooks include research notes and drafts related to Kristeller's research on the history of Universities and Humanistic education in Europe.
    - One and Two, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Three and Four, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Five and Six, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Seven, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Eight, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Nine and Ten, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Eleven and Twelve, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Thirteen and Fourteen, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Fifteen, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Sixteen, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Seventeen, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Eighteen, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Nineteen, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Twenty, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Twenty-One, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Twenty-Two, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Twenty-Three and Twenty Four, 1940s (Box 149)
    - Twenty-Five and Twenty-Six, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Twenty-Seven, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Twenty-Eight, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Twenty-Nine, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty-One through Thirty-Three, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty-Four, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty-Five, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty-Six, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty-Seven, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty-eight, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Thirty-Nine through Forty-One, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Forty-Two and Forty-Three, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Forty-Four, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Forty-Five, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Forty-Six and Forty-Seven, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Forty-Eight and Forty-Nine, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Fifty and Fifty-One, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Fifty-Two and Fifty-Three, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Fifty-Four and Fifty-Five, 1940s (Box 150)
    - Fifty-Six and Fifty-Seven, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Fifty-Eight and Fifty-Nine, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Sixty and Sixty-One, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Sixty-Two and Sixty-Three, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Sixty-Four and Sixty-Five, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Sixty-Six and Sixty-Seven, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Sixty-Eight through Seventy, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Seventy-One and Seventy-Two, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Seventy-Three and Seventy-Four, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Seventy-Five and Seventy-Six, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Seventy-Seven and Seventy-Eight, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Seventy-Nine, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Eighty through Eighty-Three, 1940s (Box 151)
    - Unnumbered Notebooks and Notes, 1940s (Box 151)
  - Subseries VII.2: Unidentified Notebooks, undated, 1945-1946
    These notebooks include Kristeller's research notes. These notebooks are not identified by project, but some include notes related to manuscript research.
    - A and B, undated (Box 151)
    - C and D, undated (Box 151)
    - E through G, undated (Box 151)
    - H through J, undated (Box 151)
    - K through M, undated (Box 151)
    - N through P, undated (Box 152)
    - Q and R, undated (Box 152)
    - S and T, undated (Box 152)
    - U and V, undated (Box 152)
    - W, undated (Box 152)
    - X, undated (Box 152)
    - Y and Z, undated (Box 152)
    - ZZ, undated (Box 152)
    - Unidentified, undated, (7 Folders) (Box 152)
    - Unidentified, 1945 (Box 152)
    - Unidentified, 1946 (Box 152)
  - Subseries VII.3: Research and Topical Notes, 1920-1990
    The Research and Topical Notes subseries includes notes, manuscript drafts, and correspondence related to numerous research projects, books, and articles. These files are arranged alphabetically by research topic.
    - General, 1941-1989, (7 Folders) (Box 152)
    - Aristotle's Rhetoric, undated (Box 152)
    - Arts Liberaux, 1966-1967 (Box 152)
    - Ermolao Barbara, undated, 1946 (Box 152)
    - Bartolomeus Facius, 1964-1965 (Box 152)
    - Buoninsegni, 1969-1971 (Box 152)
    - Cardinal Elbarada, undated (Box 152)
    - Cassirer, Ernst, 1994 (Box 152)
    - Corsin 582, 1990 (Box 152)
    - Creativity, 1982 (Box 152)
    - Cusanno, 1970-1972, 1989 (Box 152)
    - De Libri, 1948-1958 (Box 152)
    - Early Manuscripts (German), undated, 1943, (2 Folders) (Box 152)
    - Festschrift, 1958-1961 (Box 152)
    - Festschrift, 1981-1983 (Box 152)
    - Ficino Research, 1955-1985, (5 Folders) (Box 152)
    - Filosofia Greci, undated (Box 152)
    - Gilbert, Neal, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 152)
    - Humanists (Box 152)
    - Italian Humanists, 1966-1970 (Box 153)
    - Kant, 1931 September (Box 153)
    - Landino Polizano and Lorenzo di Medici, undated (Box 153)
    - Laurus Quirinus, undated (Box 153)
    - Merlan Review, 1976 (Box 153)
    - More, Henry, undated (Box 153)
    - Music and Learning in the Early Renaissance, 1946 (Box 153)
    - Nardi Article, undated (Box 153)
    - Nardi Volume Cortona, 1956-1959 (Box 153)
    - Neoplatonism and the Renaissance, 1990 (Box 153)
    - Philosophy (Box 153)
    - Pico della Mirandola, undated (Box 153)
    - Pletho, undated (Box 153)
    - Plotinus, [1928] (Box 153)
    - Pomponazzi, undated, 1955 (Box 153)
    - Proclus, 1985-1987, (3 Folders) (Box 153)
    - Purnell, Frederick, 1967 (Box 153)
    - Petrus Candidus, 1964-1967 (Box 153)
    - Religious Orders in the Renaissance, 1982 (Box 153)
    - Renaissance Aristotelianism, 1964-1965 (Box 153)
    - Renaissance Humanism, 1958-1971, (2 Folders) (Box 153)
    - Renaissance Humanism and Universities
      - General (Box 153)
      - Heidelberg, 1984-1988 (Box 153)
      - Italian Universities, (2 Folders) (Box 153)
    - Renaissanceforschung und Altertumswissenschaft, 1958-1959 (Box 153)
    - Rhetoric (Box 154)
    - Salerno, 1975-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 154)
    - Santini, 1954 (Box 154)
    - Charles B. Schmitt, 1969-1972, 1986 (Box 154)
    - Shaftsbury, undated (Box 154)
    - Scuola Normale Superiore di Pisa, 1989 (Box 154)
    - System, 1950-1951 (Box 154)
    - Tasso, undated (Box 154)
    - Viro (Box 154)
    - Vives (Box 154)
    - Unlabled, 1920s-1959, (3 Folders) (Box 154)
  - Subseries VII.4: Research Notecards
    This subseries contains notecards including bibliographic citations related to his ongoing research projects.
    - Notecards (Box 155-164)
- Series VIII: Printed Material
  This series contains printed material from Kristeller's library, some by Kristeller himself, but the majority are offprints, articles, and books by other-- many inscribed to Kristeller by the author. This series also includes lists of books and articles that formed Kristeller's personal library.
  - List of Books in Paul Oskar Kristeller's Library, (2 Folders) (Box 165)
  - List of Art Books in Paul Oskar Kristeller's Library, (2 Folders) (Box 165)
  - List of Art Books in Paul Oskar Kristeller's Library (Box 166)
  - List of Off-Prints, Papers, and Articles in Kristeller's Library, (3 Folders) (Box 166)
  - Printed Material 1926-1988 (Box 167)
    (Newsletters, Conference Programs, Lecture Announcements and Ephemera)
  - Books (Box 167)
    (many inscribed to Kristeller)
  - Books (Box 168-169)
  - Offprints and Articles
    - by Kristeller, (4 Folders) (Box 170)
    - Related to Leonardo DaVinci Manuscripts (Box 170)
    - By Others, (5 Folders) (Box 170)
    - By Others, (13 Folders) (Box 171)